[{"id": "5ff7c1662b316f4693fb679d", "question": "Which famous sandwich was formerly known as the Blue Ribbon Burger?", "answer": "Big Mac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888b", "question": "Where was King Arthur's court?", "answer": "Camelot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa22", "question": "What Surrey town is famed for its salts?", "answer": "Epsom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e7d206d333868d34d743", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the first murderer?", "answer": "Cain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ff", "question": "What are you doing if you \"yarn over\" or \"pop corn\"?", "answer": "Knitting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6de", "question": "What Winter Olympic sport event requires players to slide stones at houses?", "answer": "Curling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7de", "question": "Lake Champlain lies on the border between Vermont and which other US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b911", "question": "In the restaurant industry, what number does the kitchen commonly assign to an item that they've run out of?", "answer": "86", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b3bdfb6c85e9e634ff43", "question": "In architecture, what is the structure that forms the arms of a cross-shaped church named?", "answer": "Transept", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b48e649076251badbeaa8", "question": "Who was the first American woman in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride -- One of six women selected for NASA Astronaut Group 8, she traveled on Space Shuttle Challenger's STS-7 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f60", "question": "What supermodel plays the bride in Guns N' Roses' \"November Rain\" video?", "answer": "Stephanie Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c698", "question": "What constellation represents a hunter with a club and shield?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af3", "question": "According to the lyrics of the Counting Crows song \"Mr. Jones\", what rock legend does the singer want to be?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb5af7e83c707845b211f", "question": "What's the word for when you can't remember a word?", "answer": "Lethologica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70f", "question": "In The Twelve Days of Christmas what did my true love send to me on the third day?", "answer": "Three French Hens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec23a98dc25ca9e12ef632", "question": "What word describes \"a series of rulers from the same family\"?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b5", "question": "Which French fashion designer created the conical bra for Madonna's \"Blond Ambition\" tour?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ea", "question": "Which is the highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec5", "question": "Which Saint was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral in 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923d", "question": "What track from U2's \"The Joshua Tree\" album won a Grammy for its video?", "answer": "Where the Streets Have No Name", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e16736d4be723796b4a", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f2d", "question": "Who wrote \"Our Lady of the Flowers\" while in prison?", "answer": "Jean Genet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339776", "question": "What company did Robert Downey Jr. inherit from his father in Ironman?", "answer": "Stark Industries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b742", "question": "Who was also known as \"Black Dahlia\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Short", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ed2208d98002fdd633c5", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c79efbde8045e48466c5", "question": "Studies show dogs can see which two colors?", "answer": "Dogs can make out combinations of blue and yellow, which may explain why they prefer toys in these colors.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdfbe6d003d27d341092bce", "question": "Where is the world-famous Skytree tower located?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a987", "question": "What city named its airport after Louis Armstrong?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8b", "question": "What major God shares the same name in both Greek and Roman mythology?", "answer": "Apollo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389aa", "question": "What novel by Louisa May Alcott tells about the lives and loves of four sisters?", "answer": "Little Women", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa4", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f2", "question": "Who sang the title song for the 1978 suspense film \"Eyes of Laura Mars\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f69", "question": "What album track was the first song the Beatles ever performed on their Ed Sullivan Show debut?", "answer": "All My Loving", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa55a3c73aa70ea0b70b24", "question": "Sahti is a type of beer that is traditionally flavored with juniper and it is most likely found in which country?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e92", "question": "What movie did the villain Joan Crawford appear in?", "answer": "Mommie Dearest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c472", "question": "A camel's hump contains mostly what?", "answer": "Fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339574", "question": "In, Santa Baby by Madonna what kind of fur does she want him to slip under the tree?", "answer": "A sable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fba", "question": "What smash video features a vintage performance by the fictional band The Love Below?", "answer": "Hey Ya!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e3", "question": "Which famous actor and star of the TV show \"Dallas\" was born Harold Leek?", "answer": "Howard Keel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26e", "question": "Architect Walter Gropius founded what famous German art school in Weimar in 1919?", "answer": "The Bauhaus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989ad56cb8751d53e7d7610", "question": "What name is shared by an 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1be", "question": "How many years did it take Ferdinand Porsche, and his team, to design the VW Beetle?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e96127ccba3ffe45786e8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Arachne challenge to a weaving contest?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7ccca877e98cb97778a2b", "question": "Which country has Cayenne as its capital?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b931", "question": "What's the traditional dish served at Wimbledon?", "answer": "Strawberries and cream", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cfbe877e98cb97778a53", "question": "Miami, Florida sits on the bank of what bay?", "answer": "Biscayne Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69e3620565ad31a57c780", "question": "What was the real name of the Confederate ironclad ship that went to battle with the USS Monitor?", "answer": "CSS Virginia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57d", "question": "What ingredient does the word \"sushi\" refer to?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c412", "question": "What bird has the biggest eyes of any land animal?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338893", "question": "What is heaven to fallen Norse warriors?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ab8a16490a8cc1a6e528d", "question": "In what year was the first Call of Duty game released?", "answer": "2003", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca71", "question": "What term is applied to animals or plants that are not nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a7", "question": "What two countries edge the Victoria Falls?", "answer": "Zimbabwe and Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e92f47ccba3ffe45786bf", "question": "Who is the main protagonist of the 1932 novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "Flora Poste", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ec6006d333868d34d765", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c35", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b203", "question": "What metal item on the end of a kite string gave off the sparks in Benjamin Franklin's 1752 experiment?", "answer": "A key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b254", "question": "In what city did Rosa Parks refuse to move to the back of the bus?", "answer": "Montgomery, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3d00ff048f679a45ab45", "question": "What is a body's resistance to changes in motion or speed called?", "answer": "Inertia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdfb82b003d27d341092bbb", "question": "Where is the world's oldest royal residence still in use?", "answer": "England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a212", "question": "What was the name of the dog in the TV series \"Fraggle Rock\"?", "answer": "Sprocket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9b", "question": "What is the family name of the creator of Tobasco sauce?", "answer": "McIllhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c1", "question": "What word was intentionally omitted from the screenplay of The Godfather?", "answer": "Mafia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8b", "question": "What former World Heavyweight Champion boxer was nicknamed \"The Brown Bomber\"?", "answer": "Joe Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53a", "question": "In what State is it illegal to smoke from a pipe after sunset?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac287e83c707845b20eb", "question": "What does the X in \"X-ray\" stand for?", "answer": "\"Unknown\" type of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b885", "question": "In bowling, what would your score be if you bowled 11 strikes and a 6?", "answer": "296", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c640", "question": "By what name is Sodium Chloride better known as?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8df", "question": "What popular tourist destination is Thailand's largest island?", "answer": "Phuket", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a124", "question": "What do the prisoners call the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6e", "question": "Who developed the processed cheese spread known as Cheez Whiz?", "answer": "Edwin Traisman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e0", "question": "What fashion designer owns Maxim's restaurant in Paris?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fd23fe83fe1f2a824c4b", "question": "A representation of the Nativity scene is known as what?", "answer": "Cr\u00e8che", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5b", "question": "In 1994, Mary Ramsey replaced Natalie Merchant as the lead singer for what group?", "answer": "10,000 Maniacs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af0", "question": "What type of animal is Napoleon, in George Orwell\u2019s novel \u201cAnimal Farm?\u201d", "answer": "A pig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e60", "question": "What word comes from the capital in Hell in Milton's \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "Pandemonium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34f", "question": "What shape is the body of an Erlenmeyer flask?", "answer": "Conical", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5d285dad637d903c8822", "question": "What is Valentine's Day called in Brazil?", "answer": "Dia dos Namorados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c967", "question": "What is the fear of flying called?", "answer": "Aviatophobia or pteromerhanophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89c", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after a US state?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e88", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Minotaur?", "answer": "Human and bull", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a949961d1b4d384d5d66e", "question": "In the world of entertainment, how is \"Dana Owens\" more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e7", "question": "When did actor W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb4", "question": "What novel centres on the romances of Ursula and Gudrun Brangwen?", "answer": "Women in Love", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14048b0ee8c595b6d3999", "question": "What Shakespeare play inspired the title of Aldous Huxley's \"Brave New World\"?", "answer": "\"The Tempest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049e7ecf93664eb10486b4", "question": "What country does the rock band \"Enter Shikari\" originate from?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8601ec223966ae8f880c", "question": "\"City of God\" takes place in which Third World city?", "answer": "The slums of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b222", "question": "What city was William McKinley killed in?", "answer": "Buffalo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9384a6bd93ce3a4e5f682", "question": "Insectophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b3", "question": "In the world of business, what does DJIA stand for?", "answer": "Dow Jones Industrial Average", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cace", "question": "What is heliology the study of?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5fc66ce05a3942286e47", "question": "The Kansas City Chiefs were originally known as what?", "answer": "The Dallas Texans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a96", "question": "\"The Tortelli's\" was the first attempt at a spin-off from what TV show?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e5", "question": "In Judaism, what day of the week is considered a day of rest?", "answer": "Saturday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a438", "question": "In what country is the San Andreas Fault located?", "answer": "United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b029", "question": "What California coastal town hosted the first major rock festival in 1967?", "answer": "Monterey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89dca011619dd6d415489", "question": "Whose mom in South Park was sucked into a toilet?", "answer": "Clyde\u2019s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b859", "question": "How many rings are there on the Olympic flag?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb8", "question": "What empire arose in the Peruvian highlands around 1200 AD?", "answer": "The Inca Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339694", "question": "What film stars Woody Harrelson as a bowler that loses his hand in an accident?", "answer": "Kingpin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bd", "question": "What Broadway soundtrack was the best selling album of the 1960's?", "answer": "West Side Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdd", "question": "What popular artist co-wrote \"Justify My Love\" with Madonna?", "answer": "Lenny Kravitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3deaff048f679a45ab56", "question": "What is the only moon in the solar system that has an atmosphere?", "answer": "Titan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f6", "question": "Which character in the Simpsons was kicked out of the barbershop quartet, \"The Be Sharps\"?", "answer": "Chief Wiggum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76bd5eec85e375820b2c9", "question": "Which island is often referred to as the \"Galap\u00e1gos of Australia\"?", "answer": "Kangaroo Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d7", "question": "Which quarter of New Orleans is famous for its restaurants and jazz clubs?", "answer": "French Quarter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7eb8eb24f84e0b9f9ffde", "question": "What state borders Alabama to the north?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb9", "question": "What Caribbean island did Columbus originally name Juana?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b3", "question": "What is a parsec a unit of?", "answer": "Length", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4d", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Caged\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7f7", "question": "On what continent is the Balkan Peninsula?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21d", "question": "What city was Martin Luther King, Jr. killed in?", "answer": "Memphis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe735e8eec85e375820b255", "question": "What did John Wilkes Booth trip on as he jumped on the stage of Ford's Theater?", "answer": "Bunting", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c805", "question": "What kind of twins are also called \"dizygotic\"?", "answer": "Fraternal twins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91d", "question": "Which part of the body does the adjective \"renal\" refer to?", "answer": "Kidney", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba3bb874c93a3298b213f", "question": "What was the full name of Queen Elizabeth The Queen Mother", "answer": "Elizabeth Angela Marguerite Bowes-Lyon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc6", "question": "What kind of flower does saffron come from?", "answer": "A crocus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e99a0ebfabb9c85d8a974", "question": "Whose first wife was actress Jane Wyman?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc7", "question": "What Los Angeles neighborhood witnessed six days of rioting in 1965?", "answer": "Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c311", "question": "What element are diamonds made of?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e2", "question": "Who chose her new name in 1953 to honor a Danish surgeon named Christian Hamburger?", "answer": "Christine Jorgensen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a16", "question": "What was the name of the guy Sam has a crush on in the movie \"Sixteen Candles\"?", "answer": "Jake Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906837bff9c0647b50a80a7", "question": "Which electronic duo did The Weeknd collaborate with for his song, \"Starboy\"?", "answer": "Daft Punk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338994", "question": "How many of the gifts in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\" include humans?", "answer": "5", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae06", "question": "Which two tools are depicted on the former Soviet Union's flag?", "answer": "Hammer and sickle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db5", "question": "What title character of a classic 1891 novel is arrested at Stonehenge?", "answer": "Tess of the D'Urbervilles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede4316ce05a3942286dd9", "question": "Parts of the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\" were shot in what African country?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a697", "question": "KODAK is headquartered In what U.S. City?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49d", "question": "Which European country's name is derived from the term \"hollow land\"?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6af", "question": "What letter represents the speed of light in physics notations?", "answer": "c", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59220424a4edfd43a087ade5", "question": "What are the colors of the counters used in the original \"Connect 4\" game?", "answer": "Red and yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b026", "question": "What Native American leader surrendered at Skeleton Canyon in 1886?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86e", "question": "What fruit is a hybrid of the mandarin orange and the grapefruit?", "answer": "The tangelo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7e713b24f84e0b9f9ffb6", "question": "Who narrated the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f4f7ff048f679a45aace", "question": "Microphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Small things", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ba", "question": "What does a phobophobe fear?", "answer": "Fear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb8", "question": "What model was married to musician Dave Navarro?", "answer": "Carmen Electra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c6e0fbde8045e48466bb", "question": "How is Lyme disease transmitted?", "answer": "The bite of blacklegged ticks infected with the bacterium\u00a0Borrelia burgdorferi\u00a0or rarely,\u00a0the bacterium Borrelia mayonii.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ac", "question": "Which Kingdom is Greenland a part of?", "answer": "The Kingdom of Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9f", "question": "What is the fear of the color purple known as?", "answer": "Porphyrophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee7", "question": "How many bottles unexpectedly appear in the last verse of Police song \"Message in a Bottle\"?", "answer": "A hundred billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3f", "question": "What is the capital of China?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80d", "question": "What is the basic flavoring of Kahlua?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fc96a4edfd43a087adc0", "question": "Sweet Baby Broccoli is another name for what vegetable?", "answer": "Broccolini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7b55ff048f679a45abf5", "question": "King, Coho and Silver are subspecies of what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6e", "question": "What medical facility was founded in Rochester, Minnesota, in the late 1800s?", "answer": "Mayo Clinic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff141a8b0ee8c595b6d39a5", "question": "Who wrote \"James and the Giant Peach\"?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c33", "question": "Gilbert Stuart is best known for his work in what genre of painting?", "answer": "Portraits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feba9f67e83c707845b20da", "question": "What is a group of jelly fish called?", "answer": "A smack", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918c", "question": "Which witch is flattened by a house in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50a", "question": "How many squares are there on a Snakes and Ladders board?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72f", "question": "In the Steve Miller song \"The Joker\", what men\u2019s name do \"some people call him\"?", "answer": "Maurice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd1c877e98cb97778954", "question": "What percentage of the River Nile is located in Egypt?", "answer": "22%", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133926d", "question": "Which rap star was born Cordozar Calvin Broadus, Jr.?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f668ff048f679a45aadc", "question": "What layer of the Earth's atmosphere makes radio communications possible?", "answer": "Ionosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d7", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Dnieper river?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a5e790aac110e4167077", "question": "What type of cherries are used for Kriek lambics?", "answer": "Sour Morello", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c256", "question": "What is the SI physical unit of dynamic viscosity?", "answer": "Pascal-second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c1", "question": "What CEO bounced back after being fired by Henry Ford II in 1978?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af9", "question": "The bands Whitesnake and Rainbow were both splinter groups from what British rock band?", "answer": "Deep Purple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f31301dd7bf43be5e814", "question": "What does AFLAC stand for in the US?", "answer": "American Family Life Assurance Company of Columbus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242ee4be4723ccac2218f", "question": "In Jane Austen\u2019s \"Pride and Prejudice\", what is the name of the pompous clergyman who marries Elizabeth\u2019s sister, Charlotte?", "answer": "Mr. Collins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339675", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the tablecloth in the Simpsons' kitchen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94d0b65ea27d7a1303aed2", "question": "In a standard deck of cards, which of the face cards are the only ones whose hair is colored in a deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ea43b24f84e0b9f9ffd2", "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?", "answer": "Regular Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa8a06ce05a3942286ed4", "question": "What famous athlete starred in the film \"Dirty Dozen\"?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a450", "question": "How many states does the Appalachian Trail traverse?", "answer": "14", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60160173fe83fe1f2a824c5f", "question": "According to a famous Polish legend, which creature made a blanket to keep baby Jesus warm?", "answer": "A spider, which is why Poles have a great reverence for spiders.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb56e65ff7d326b622a92", "question": "This is the Southeast Asian method of dying fabric using wax to create designs?", "answer": "Batik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ead", "question": "What poet slammed unscrupulous bookseller Edmund Curll in his 1728 poem \"The Dunciad\"?", "answer": "Alexander Pope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e7b506d333868d34d741", "question": "In 1929, what did Clarence Birdseye introduce?", "answer": "Frozen food", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59220625a4edfd43a087adec", "question": "Gluten is a type of what?", "answer": "Protein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9031501dd7bf43be5e86d", "question": "What was the original name for Gummy Bears?", "answer": "Dancing Bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a749", "question": "What US city was originally called Terminus in 1837?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c410", "question": "DuPont chemist Wallace Carothers developed what new plastic material in 1930?", "answer": "Nylon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008da2df4f3bc4a292f8613", "question": "Why did the British royals change their family name to the House of Windsor in 1917?", "answer": "The original name, Saxe-Coburgs, was derived from Queen Victoria's German husband, Albert. That did not sit well during World War I.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc3126de0eb824d4052ea", "question": "What is the oldest bridge across Venice's Grand Canal?", "answer": "Rialto Bridge -- Built by architect-engineer Antonio da Ponte and his nephew, the bridge is supported by 6,000 timber piles.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6a", "question": "What name was Haitian dictator Francois Duvalier better known by?", "answer": "Papa Doc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3ad4ff048f679a45ab2f", "question": "What is the shape of DNA known as?", "answer": "Double Helix", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a858", "question": "Which river does the Brooklyn Bridge cross?", "answer": "East River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969f", "question": "Who is Brian mistaken for in the 1979 movie \"Life of Brian\"?", "answer": "The Messiah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb2", "question": "What disease killed 20,000 Parisians in 1832?", "answer": "Cholera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccc", "question": "The song \"Suite: Judy Blue Eyes\" was inspired by Stephen Stills' breakup with whom?", "answer": "Judy Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94417ccba3ffe45786d1", "question": "What is the atomic number of Californium?", "answer": "98", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e93397ccba3ffe45786c3", "question": "What food item does the painting technique \"Tempera\" commonly uses as a binder?", "answer": "Egg yolks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22d", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c599", "question": "What fungus is used in making bread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924f", "question": "What movie's first batch of soap is made out of fat from liposuction clinics?", "answer": "Fight Club's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a4", "question": "How many bones are there in the human skull?", "answer": "22", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73564eec85e375820b24a", "question": "Who said, \"A state of society where men may not speak their minds cannot long endure.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad11", "question": "By what nickname was Simon Bolivar was also known as?", "answer": "The Liberator", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbf", "question": "Whose garden is infiltrated by Peter Rabbit?", "answer": "Mr. McGregor's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae9566574a5ce6b56b8254", "question": "What animals does a hippophobe fear?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592205cea4edfd43a087adea", "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59bb2a9dc9bff04efae6d761", "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339485", "question": "Who stars as Walter Fielding Jr. in the 1986 movie \"The Money Pit\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66a", "question": "Anna's, Calliope, and Ruby-throated are species of what bird?", "answer": "Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbb", "question": "What novelist of westerns went by his middle name, since his first was Pearl?", "answer": "Zane Grey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf71", "question": "What product was originally manufactured by communications giant Nokia?", "answer": "Paper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a4", "question": "What does the equation E=mc2 represent?", "answer": "Mass-energy equivalency", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f4135cb9e8bda6821366", "question": "By what other name is the folk tale \"Cinderella\" also known as?", "answer": "The Little Glass Slipper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe000791cf6db9ac4808d12", "question": "What are the Philippines named after?", "answer": "Spain's King Philip II", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ee33fe83fe1f2a824c07", "question": "David Jung is considered by many to be the originator of which famous food?", "answer": "Fortune cookies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aaba01dd7bf43be5e75f", "question": "Chartreuse is a color between yellow and what?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba141874c93a3298b2124", "question": "Caracas is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c64d877e98cb977789b6", "question": "What U.S. city is known for its hot chicken?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9d", "question": "What is the profession of Jon Cryer's character on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Chiropractor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f7", "question": "In the movie \"Clockwork Orange\", Alex DeLarge drank what?", "answer": "Milk Plus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a5", "question": "What famous landmark is located in Agra, India?", "answer": "Taj Mahal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31e", "question": "What was Keanu Reeves' alias in the film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Neo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d92", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Ossessione\" based on?", "answer": "The Postman Always Rings Twice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00b", "question": "What Merrilee Rush hit was written by Chip Taylor, the brother of actor Jon Voight?", "answer": "Angel of the Morning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35c", "question": "Where is Lake Como?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b1745eebb2d29f81593b704", "question": "Which duo had a 1987 Christmas hit with the song \"Always on My Mind\"?", "answer": "The Pet Shop Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339173", "question": "Who played Luke Skywalker in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "Mark Hamill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf21", "question": "Tony Drago is a snooker professional from which country?", "answer": "Malta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cb0a877e98cb97778a12", "question": "What nation does the island of Okinawa belong to?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51274ff04d658268c92d0", "question": "What was the most popular drink in colonial America?", "answer": "Nearly everyone in colonial America drank\u00a0tea, which explains the uproar when the British levied a tax on their favorite drink.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d4", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a3c839a039f3d7859290ffa", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed the blacksmith, Quint Asper?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae05", "question": "What did JFK call \"the most hazardous and dangerous and greatest adventure on which man has ever embarked\"?", "answer": "Putting a man on the moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339632", "question": "In the 1995 movie \"Babe\", what Christmas carol does Babe sing?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a94b161d1b4d384d5d670", "question": "What is Dana Elaine Owens' stage name?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d9", "question": "How many US states are named after a president?", "answer": "One - Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e805e5de59ea584496fead", "question": "Which South African town was severely damaged by the Boland Earthquake in September 1969?", "answer": "Tulbagh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388db", "question": "Who is the Greek god of the grape and vine, music, irrationality, intoxication, dancing and ecstasy?", "answer": "Dionysus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51cecff04d658268c931f", "question": "What famous general was once attacked by rabbits?", "answer": "Napoleon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60077f91bd51d85e222ab63d", "question": "What school of art grew out of the poetry of Romanian-born Tristan Tzara?", "answer": "The\u00a0Dada\u00a0school of art, or Dadaism was born out of the widespread disillusionment created by World War I.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66d", "question": "What are baby bears called?", "answer": "Cubs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79d", "question": "What is the only moon in our solar system to spin in a direction opposite of its planet's rotation?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc16a0469bb8041d07a08d", "question": "What is the Japanese word for \"dog\"?", "answer": "Inu", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c384", "question": "Wallace Carothers invented nylon while working as a scientist for what company?", "answer": "DuPont", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c1a49076251badbeacd", "question": "Which First Lady was the first born outside of America?", "answer": "Louisa Adams, the wife of John Quincy Adams, was born in London.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f0c06682715b82711cd9", "question": "What does the RIP stand for in Latin?", "answer": "Requiescat in pace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c6", "question": "What 1928 novel by D.H. Lawrence was banned in the US until 1959?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a222", "question": "Vaselina and Brillantino were alternate names which film?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb45", "question": "A hobbyist referred to as a \"numismatist\" studies or collects what?", "answer": "Coins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e76", "question": "What superteam includes Cosmic Boy, Saturn Girl and Lightning Boy?", "answer": "The Legion of Super-Heroes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971d", "question": "Sandra Bullock won the 2009 Best Actress Oscar for her role in which movie?", "answer": "The Blind Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbef76ce05a3942286ef9", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Heart of Glass\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87c", "question": "Sinologists study what?", "answer": "China and Chinese topics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a99901dd7bf43be5e750", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what did the cat take?", "answer": "The rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f03", "question": "In what 1986 movie does Jeremy Irons scale South America's Iguazu Falls?", "answer": "The Mission", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991c", "question": "Who occupied the center square on the game show \u201cThe Hollywood Squares\u201d from 1998\u00ad to 2002?", "answer": "Whoopi Goldberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac7b", "question": "Who became prime minister of Cuba in 1959?", "answer": "Fidel Castro", "category": "history"}]